<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startup Product Manager</title>
    <description>On building products that people love and use</description>
    <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.startupproductmanager.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>If you haven&#39;t talked to a customer today, you are doing it wrong</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Great advice for entrepreneurs and Product Managers from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/startupljackson&quot;&gt;Startup L Jackson&lt;/a&gt;. In effect he asks us to come up with a framework that guides/informs your intuition. Keep refining the framework everytime you meet someone new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there are a few specific examples of how you can keep refining it based on who you meet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__Anyone and Everyone: __&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ask everyone you meet what they believe, and why. When you’re talking to your Cousin Eddie, ask him about his favorite apps. How does he buy stuff? Does he watch YouTube? How does he find new restaurants or plan his travel? How does he advertise his small business? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__Founders: __&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you meet other founders, ask them how their business works. Treat them as experts with insights that can help you improve your framework. Who are their customers? What do their customers love about the product? What have they tried that customers hated? How do they explain the product to customers? They’re building a marketplace, cool! How much do providers have to make to stay engaged? How many uses before a buyer sticks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__Customers: __&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And if you have an area you’re working, talk to customers. Every day. Talk to users of your product, active, inactive, new, and old. Talk to people who don’t want to use your product. Talk to people who are using a competitor’s product. Talk to customers of products in adjacent markets. Now, reread this paragraph and &lt;strong&gt;replace talk with listen.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://startupljackson.com/post/102141918295/the-counterintuitive-thing-about-counterintuitive&quot;&gt;The full article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2014/11/the-counterintuitive-thing-about-counterintuitive-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2014/11/the-counterintuitive-thing-about-counterintuitive-things/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conflict Strategies for Product Managers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw this article on HBR (it is from last year). It is meant for “nice people”, but I think these are just as applicable to Product Managers, who often need to wield &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sachinrekhi.com/blog/2013/02/19/the-most-underrated-product-management-skill-influence-without-authority&quot;&gt;influence without authority&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Teams need conflict to function effectively.  Conflict allows the team to come to terms with difficult situations, to synthesize diverse perspectives, and to make sure solutions are well thought-out.  Conflict is uncomfortable, but it is the source of true innovation and also a critical process in identifying and mitigating risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a PM, you need to be comfortable with a healthy level of conflict. Healthy Conflict is a sign of passionate people who stand for something. If you are not getting push back on your ideas, you may be settling for mediocre local maxima. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The secret of having healthy conflict and maintaining your self-image as a nice person is all in the mindset and the delivery. To start shifting your mindset, think about your value to the team not in how often you agree, but in how often you add unique value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow! and now for a couple of specific tips: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Use “and,” not “but.” &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May Sound cheesy, but this is a flavor of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uxmag.com/articles/yes-and-the-improv-of-ux&quot;&gt;Yes And&lt;/a&gt; Principle in Improv. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ask for help. Another tactic for “nice conflict” is to be mildly self-deprecating and to own the misunderstanding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wrong way to be a hero is by avoiding conflict or “taking one for the team”. Don’t be that kind of a heroic PM. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.hbr.org/2013/12/conflict-strategies-for-nice-people/&quot;&gt;Full Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2014/11/conflict-strategies-for-product-managers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2014/11/conflict-strategies-for-product-managers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Short Form Blogging</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Negotiate a comfort zone on two axes.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Traffic is irrelevant&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Have fun. Blogging is not your job. Don’t add it to your to-do list. If it’s not fun and you’re not done? Screw it. Take the baby to the park instead.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This “short-form” post from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ginatrapani&quot;&gt;Gina Tripani&lt;/a&gt; inspired me to get back at it again. Nope, no in-depth medium style pieces, probably a lot of tools/tips style posts and a bunch of link posts (like this one). The last time I wanted to post, I ended up &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johnotander/pixyll/&quot;&gt;updating my theme&lt;/a&gt;, so fingers cross if it’ll work out this time. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2014/11/short-form-blogging/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2014/11/short-form-blogging/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seasons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the harsh winters, I really like the New England area for the four seasons and how each season has its unique beauty. Here is a snapshot of how the same place looks in Fall &amp;amp; Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//instagram.com/p/jXKuhFql_u/embed/&quot; width=&quot;612&quot; height=&quot;710&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2014/01/new-england-fall-winter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2014/01/new-england-fall-winter/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Windows 8 Is The Perfect OS That Nobody Wants</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People care about speed, efficiency, clarity, and delight. But a phone interface matching a laptop interface is about as important as socks matching underwear. It’s nice, but on most days, probably the last priority on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Takeaway&lt;/strong&gt;: Your design could be great on paper and executed perfectly, but it still has to solve a real problem. Props to Microsoft for trying though and setting the tone on this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2013/12/windows-8-perfect-os-that-nobody-wants/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2013/12/windows-8-perfect-os-that-nobody-wants/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>London Heathrow airport has an interesting way of surveying customers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/images/heathrow-survey.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Heathrow Survey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 21:14:59 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2013/10/london-heathrow-airport-has-an-interesting-way-of-surveying-customers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2013/10/london-heathrow-airport-has-an-interesting-way-of-surveying-customers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>iPhone 5C &amp; 5S : Observations of a Product Manager</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is already a lot of analysis on new iPhone 5 C (for color) and 5 S (for sensors) including the usual fanboys such as&lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2013/09/iphone_5c_5c_event&quot;&gt; Gruber&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/10/iphone-5c/&quot;&gt; Siegler&lt;/a&gt; etc,.) and the haters (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thestreet.com/story/12033242/1/google-laughs-at-the-new-iphones.html#!&quot;&gt;sarcastically indicating that “Google laughs at the new phone”&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/images/iphone5c_2x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iphone 5c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to analyze it from a Product Manager’s perspective.  Wall Street’s initial reaction is pessimism.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/finance?chdnp=1&amp;amp;chdd=1&amp;amp;chds=1&amp;amp;chdv=1&amp;amp;chvs=maximized&amp;amp;chdeh=0&amp;amp;chfdeh=0&amp;amp;chdet=1378918680000&amp;amp;chddm=465&amp;amp;chls=IntervalBasedLine&amp;amp;q=NASDAQ:AAPL&amp;amp;&amp;amp;fct=big&amp;amp;ei=0zUxUsCmCO2F0QHIjAE&quot;&gt; Apple’s stock is down 5% the day after&lt;/a&gt;, but the fact that Apple doesn’t do what the Street wants it to do, gives me optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observations on the 5C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The creation of 5C is interesting for its positioning and pricing. Apple diverged from its usual play of bumping the price down by $100. It packaged the product differently, added color and has made what is basically the iPhone 5 a “New Product”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5C is now the “bread and butter” product for Apple. It is the first product featured on the website and the 5S is repeatedly positioned as a cutting edge product, and in many ways seems like a decoy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5C is meant to “pull up” those who would have otherwise gone for the free product, but also meant to make them feel good about the product they have. (that color!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you hate those 5C colors, you are not the target market! Anecdotally, I have heard that there is a lot of excitement about the colors from teens and new grads. Parents can expect to spend on the 5C.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apple 5C plus the $30 cases (which will be ALL margin) will keep the bottom line happy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The fact that the 32GB 5C and the 16GB 5S are the same price is a little head-scratching.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am surprised Apple&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/10/do-i-like-the-iphone-5c-case-non/&quot;&gt; let “hon” slip through the cracks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observations on the 5S&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5S is very interesting from the perspective of iterative product development. I don’t know if it transpired this way, but I can envision someone doing the “Thai food approach” (aka the Similans approach) to each aspect of how iPhones are used and looking at how that experience can be fixed or improved. The idea is that you categorize / prioritize each area in a chili-meter, much like a Thai restaurant rates their food for spicy-ness. Here is my shot at de-constructing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NoVW62mwSQQ&quot;&gt; take a lot of pictures on their iPhones&lt;/a&gt;. So, the thinking is “Let’s make the camera amazing””. The iPhone 6c (my name for the next year model when this camera becomes more mainstream) would become be the final nail in the coffin of Point and Shoot cameras, if they aren’t already dead. 3.5 chillies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People buy a lot of games on their iPhones. It amounts for&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.appannie.com/app-annie-index-market-q2-2013/&quot;&gt; 40%&lt;/a&gt; of the total app store downloads. So, Let’s put a 64-bit processor in there to make it FAST! Nintendo 3DS is a failure, and 2DS is now on notice. Legit gaming consoles (like Kinect/Xbox, Wii, Play Station) will be the DSLRs and handheld gaming consoles will die. (not that you already didnt know it). 4 chillies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better battery was on&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uswitch.com/mobiles/news/2013/09/iphone_5s_better_battery_fingerprint_scanner_are_most_wanted_features_says_survey/&quot;&gt; everyone’s wishlist&lt;/a&gt;: Oh yeah, and we have also added a 64-bit processor to it, which could make matters worse. How about we add a new processor (the M7) for some of the more battery intensive tasks. Oh, that also puts a whole new category of apps on steroids and helps us get into the market with Fitbit, Fuelband etc,.? SWEET! (although it could very well have been the other way around, where M7 was introduced to get into that category and had the benefit of preserving battery life) 5 chillies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People tend to lose their phones and passcodes are a pain (According to Apple, 50% dont have it enabled). Typing complicated password for buying apps is a pain, and we have data that X% of users abandon buying apps (or In app purchases) at the password stage, so Let’s make that easy. Let’s have a fingerprint sensor to unlock the phone AND make it easy to buy apps/music from the phone. This makes our ecosystem even more stronger. Win-win. 3 chillies for painpoint and 5 chillies for upside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. This post is a bit of a brain dump, but figured I’d get back into the habit and also join in on this conversation. What are your thoughts? Which model are you going to buy?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 22:25:08 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2013/09/iphone-5c-5s-product-management/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2013/09/iphone-5c-5s-product-management/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sweat the details</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Paying attention to the little details, the ones that no one might ever notice, is a great way to take pride in your craft. When those details DO get noticed, you will show your customers and users that you care. Plus they are a great way to add character and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2011/05/show-some-personality-in-your-apps/&quot;&gt;show some personality in your apps&lt;/a&gt;. Through &lt;a href=&quot;http://graysky.org/&quot;&gt;Mike Champion&lt;/a&gt;, I found this great tumblr blog called &lt;a href=&quot;http://littlebigdetails.com/&quot;&gt;Little Big Details&lt;/a&gt; which has a great collection of such details. A great site to get inspired and know that those little big details do get noticed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/legends2k&quot;&gt;legends2k &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out : &lt;a href=&quot;http://littlebigdetails.com/&quot;&gt;Little Big Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 17:38:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2012/12/sweat-the-details/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2012/12/sweat-the-details/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips for Highly Effective QR Codes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QR_code&quot;&gt;QR codes&lt;/a&gt; are everywhere these days. Yes, literally everywhere, from restaurant tables to Train station to bananas. (Can you believe it? On Bananas!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/images/banana-qr-code-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Banana qr code small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While their usage is not quite mainstream (yet), it is growing steadily and I expect the adoption to really take off when iOS joins the other popular mobile platforms (Android and to some Windows Phone) and supports QR Code natively.  There are helpful posts on  &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/29449/How-to-Create-a-QR-Code-in-4-Quick-Steps.aspx&quot;&gt;how to create your qrcode in 4 easy steps&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/30678/9-Unique-Ways-to-Generate-Leads-With-QR-Codes.aspx&quot;&gt;how they can be used to generate leads&lt;/a&gt; . In this post, I’ll give you some power-user tips to generate Robust QR Codes and increase your chances of conversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways a QR Code is like someone casually browsing your website. They start out as a casual onlooker of QR Code and ends up as a lead. If you think of it as a funnel (Like all marketers, I love funnels), here are five tips to make each step of the funnel effective :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.** Make your QR code attractive**: Yes, you read that right. You can make QR Codes attractive. For example, you can customize it with your logo, use the same colors as your brand or identity so that it attracts attention. A word of caution though, especially when you are trying fancy things like putting your logo on the QRCode). Anytime you manually do anything with the QRCode, make sure you test it thoroughly, ensure that it can be scanned and ensure that you haven’t accidentally corrupted the code itself). Sticking your logo at the center of the code, with a white border (like in the example below, should usually be good). Here are a couple of examples of customized QRCodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/images/qrcode.short_.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qrcode short&quot; /&gt; Customized QR Code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/images/qrcode.high_.gray-with-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qrcode high gray with logo&quot; /&gt; QR Code Customized with Logo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make your QR Code easy to scan&lt;/strong&gt;: Use a URL shortener so that you are encoding lesser information, and consider picking level H (for high level of error correction). A higher level of error correction increases the likelihood that your code will be scanned, even when it is exposed to adverse conditions (like bad weather, or the code is in a banana). Here is an example showing a QRCode with a long URL: http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/30678/9-Unique-Ways-to-Generate-Leads-With-QR-Codes.aspx and the same code but now representing a shortened URL: http://hub.am/NKxvQr Any guesses on which will be picked up faster by the phone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/images/qrcode.long_.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qrcode long url&quot; /&gt; QR Code with regular, un-shortened URL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/images/qrcode.short_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qrcode short url&quot; /&gt; QR Code with shortened URL has bigger “handles”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Make sure your QR Code takes to a mobile optimized page&lt;/strong&gt;: All your efforts in making your QRCode attractive will be of no use, if your leads land on a page that is not optimized for mobile. You should also consider content that is mobile friendly (such as a video)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Think beyond URLs&lt;/strong&gt; : Think beyond URLs, make it contextual and make it relevant. For example, A QR code in a business card should be that of a VCF file. Remember that QR Codes are not restricted to just URLs. You can have QR codes for a lot of different categories including YouTube Videos, Google Maps Location, Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, FourSquare, Telephone Number, SMS Message, Email Address, Email Message, Contact Details (VCARD), Event (VCALENDAR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Try, Measure, Fix, Repeat:&lt;/strong&gt; QR Codes are a great way to bridge the gap between online and offline marketing. Use utm_campaign codes using a tracking URL builder when encoding your URLs (which gives you one more reason to use a URL shortener). If you use these codes, you can exactly tell how many visits you are getting from the QR Code and how many of those are converting to leads&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you used QR Codes successfully in your marketing campaigns? How did you make the most out of it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2012/07/5-tips-for-highly-effective-qr-codes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2012/07/5-tips-for-highly-effective-qr-codes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Focus on Intent, not Implementation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When talking to your customers and users, it is important to synthesize the information to make sure you are not just “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/show/15297&quot;&gt;delivering faster horses&lt;/a&gt;” (and apparently, there is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2011/08/henry_ford_never_said_the_fast.html&quot;&gt;no evidence that Henry Ford actually said it,&lt;/a&gt; but I digress.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://29.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l4srykesbA1qz6pqio1_500.png&quot; alt=&quot;Henry Ford Quote&quot; /&gt;). When you are working onbrand new features, you likely are talking to a lot of power users and early adopters. Given how well they know about your current product, it is quite likely that they will tell you not only the “what” of the feature but also give you insights on the “how”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So It becomes important to distinguish between what the user says by way of implementation and what the user’s real intent is. There are a couple of cues that can alert you to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the user focusing on the feature or are they talking about the benefit they’d derive from the feature? (To continue the faster horse analogy above, are they asking for shinier new wheels with additional spare wheels (which are features), or are they wishing that they get to a place faster (which is a benefit)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://scotchandcode.com/2011/11/23/356/&quot;&gt;Scotch and Code&lt;/a&gt;, I found another useful way. When the user is talking about the feature/app, are they saying “IT can do this” or are they saying “I can do this”. This subtle shift in perspective is a cue on whether the user is focusing and more importantly give a sense for whether the user thinks of your app as a tool that empowers them to do what they want to accomplish. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, here is a good example of how the focus is on the user’s intent. The Spilt keyboard in the iPad, accounts for the fact that people are going to tap on the empty spaces near the keys along the edge AND it guesses the user’s intent and magically makes those taps in empty spaces to the adjoining letter. Here is an illustration of this nifty trick: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/images/ios-split-keyboard-hidden-keys.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ios split keyboard hidden keys&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Image via &lt;a href=&quot;http://ios.finerthingsin.com/post/16982049392/ipad-keyboard-phantom-buttons&quot;&gt;http://ios.finerthingsin.com/post/16982049392/ipad-keyboard-phantom-buttons&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go ahead, try it out in your iPad. This is a classic example of focusing on the user’s intent, and not on the specifics of a given implementation. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 11:28:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2012/04/focus-on-intent-not-implementation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2012/04/focus-on-intent-not-implementation/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
