<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Startup Product Manager</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://anandrajaram.github.io/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://anandrajaram.github.io" />
<updated>2013-12-27T17:39:23-05:00</updated>
<id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/</id>
<author>
  <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
  <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io/</uri>
  <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 8 Is The Perfect OS That Nobody Wants]]></title>
  <link>http://www.fastcodesign.com/3023244/microsofts-windows-8-is-the-perfect-os-that-nobody-wants</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2013/12/windows-8-perfect-os-that-nobody-wants</id>
  <published>2013-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People care about speed, efficiency, clarity, and delight. But a phone interface matching a laptop interface is about as important as socks matching underwear. It’s nice, but on most days, probably the last priority on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Takeaway&lt;/strong&gt;: Your design could be great on paper and executed perfectly, but it still has to solve a real problem. Props to Microsoft for trying though and setting the tone on this.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2013/12/windows-8-perfect-os-that-nobody-wants/&quot;&gt;Windows 8 Is The Perfect OS That Nobody Wants&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on December 27, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[London Heathrow airport has an interesting way of surveying customers]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2013/10/london-heathrow-airport-has-an-interesting-way-of-surveying-customers/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2013/10/london-heathrow-airport-has-an-interesting-way-of-surveying-customers</id>
  <published>2013-10-23T01:14:59Z</published>
  <updated>2013-10-23T01:14:59Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/20131022-210950.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/20131022-210950.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20131022-210950.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2013/10/london-heathrow-airport-has-an-interesting-way-of-surveying-customers/&quot;&gt;London Heathrow airport has an interesting way of surveying customers&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on October 23, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone 5C & 5S : Observations of a Product Manager]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2013/09/iphone-5c-5s-product-management/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2013/09/iphone-5c-5s-product-management</id>
  <published>2013-09-13T02:25:08Z</published>
  <updated>2013-09-13T02:25:08Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is already a lot of analysis on new iPhone 5 C (for color) and 5 S (for sensors) including the usual fanboys such as&lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/2013/09/iphone_5c_5c_event&quot;&gt; Gruber&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/10/iphone-5c/&quot;&gt; Siegler&lt;/a&gt; etc,.) and the haters (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thestreet.com/story/12033242/1/google-laughs-at-the-new-iphones.html#!&quot;&gt;sarcastically indicating that &amp;quot;Google laughs at the new phone&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/iphone5c_2x.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/iphone5c_2x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iphone 5c&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to analyze it from a Product Manager&amp;#39;s perspective.  Wall Street&amp;#39;s initial reaction is pessimism.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/finance?chdnp=1&amp;amp;chdd=1&amp;amp;chds=1&amp;amp;chdv=1&amp;amp;chvs=maximized&amp;amp;chdeh=0&amp;amp;chfdeh=0&amp;amp;chdet=1378918680000&amp;amp;chddm=465&amp;amp;chls=IntervalBasedLine&amp;amp;q=NASDAQ:AAPL&amp;amp;&amp;amp;fct=big&amp;amp;ei=0zUxUsCmCO2F0QHIjAE&quot;&gt; Apple&amp;#39;s stock is down 5% the day after&lt;/a&gt;, but the fact that Apple doesn&amp;#39;t do what the Street wants it to do, gives me optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observations on the 5C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creation of 5C is interesting for its positioning and pricing. Apple diverged from its usual play of bumping the price down by $100. It packaged the product differently, added color and has made what is basically the iPhone 5 a &amp;quot;New Product&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5C is now the &amp;quot;bread and butter&amp;quot; product for Apple. It is the first product featured on the website and the 5S is repeatedly positioned as a cutting edge product, and in many ways seems like a decoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5C is meant to &amp;quot;pull up&amp;quot; those who would have otherwise gone for the free product, but also meant to make them feel good about the product they have. (that color!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you hate those 5C colors, you are not the target market! Anecdotally, I have heard that there is a lot of excitement about the colors from teens and new grads. Parents can expect to spend on the 5C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple 5C plus the $30 cases (which will be ALL margin) will keep the bottom line happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fact that the 32GB 5C and the 16GB 5S are the same price is a little head-scratching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am surprised Apple&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/10/do-i-like-the-iphone-5c-case-non/&quot;&gt; let &amp;quot;hon&amp;quot; slip through the cracks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observations on the 5S&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5S is very interesting from the perspective of iterative product development. I don’t know if it transpired this way, but I can envision someone doing the &amp;quot;Thai food approach&amp;quot; (aka the Similans approach) to each aspect of how iPhones are used and looking at how that experience can be fixed or improved. The idea is that you categorize / prioritize each area in a chili-meter, much like a Thai restaurant rates their food for spicy-ness. Here is my shot at de-constructing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NoVW62mwSQQ&quot;&gt; take a lot of pictures on their iPhones&lt;/a&gt;. So, the thinking is &amp;quot;Let&amp;#39;s make the camera amazing&amp;quot;&amp;quot;. The iPhone 6c (my name for the next year model when this camera becomes more mainstream) would become be the final nail in the coffin of Point and Shoot cameras, if they aren&amp;#39;t already dead. 3.5 chillies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People buy a lot of games on their iPhones. It amounts for&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.appannie.com/app-annie-index-market-q2-2013/&quot;&gt; 40%&lt;/a&gt; of the total app store downloads. So, Let&amp;#39;s put a 64-bit processor in there to make it FAST! Nintendo 3DS is a failure, and 2DS is now on notice. Legit gaming consoles (like Kinect/Xbox, Wii, Play Station) will be the DSLRs and handheld gaming consoles will die. (not that you already didnt know it). 4 chillies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better battery was on&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uswitch.com/mobiles/news/2013/09/iphone_5s_better_battery_fingerprint_scanner_are_most_wanted_features_says_survey/&quot;&gt; everyone&amp;#39;s wishlist&lt;/a&gt;: Oh yeah, and we have also added a 64-bit processor to it, which could make matters worse. How about we add a new processor (the M7) for some of the more battery intensive tasks. Oh, that also puts a whole new category of apps on steroids and helps us get into the market with Fitbit, Fuelband etc,.? SWEET! (although it could very well have been the other way around, where M7 was introduced to get into that category and had the benefit of preserving battery life) 5 chillies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People tend to lose their phones and passcodes are a pain (According to Apple, 50% dont have it enabled). Typing complicated password for buying apps is a pain, and we have data that X% of users abandon buying apps (or In app purchases) at the password stage, so Let&amp;#39;s make that easy. Let&amp;#39;s have a fingerprint sensor to unlock the phone AND make it easy to buy apps/music from the phone. This makes our ecosystem even more stronger. Win-win. 3 chillies for painpoint and 5 chillies for upside&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. This post is a bit of a brain dump, but figured I&amp;#39;d get back into the habit and also join in on this conversation. What are your thoughts? Which model are you going to buy?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2013/09/iphone-5c-5s-product-management/&quot;&gt;iPhone 5C & 5S : Observations of a Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on September 13, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweat the details]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/12/sweat-the-details/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/12/sweat-the-details</id>
  <published>2012-12-02T22:38:18Z</published>
  <updated>2012-12-02T22:38:18Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Paying attention to the little details, the ones that no one might ever notice, is a great way to take pride in your craft. When those details &lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2758/4517270586_764b7f421c_q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;DO get noticed, you will show your customers and users that you care. Plus they are a great way to add character and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2011/05/show-some-personality-in-your-apps/&quot;&gt;show some personality in your apps&lt;/a&gt;. Through &lt;a href=&quot;http://graysky.org/&quot;&gt;Mike Champion&lt;/a&gt;, I found this great tumblr blog called &lt;a href=&quot;http://littlebigdetails.com/&quot;&gt;Little Big Details&lt;/a&gt; which has a great collection of such details. A great site to get inspired and know that those little big details do get noticed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/legends2k&quot;&gt;legends2k &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out : &lt;a href=&quot;http://littlebigdetails.com/&quot;&gt;Little Big Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/12/sweat-the-details/&quot;&gt;Sweat the details&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on December 02, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Tips for Highly Effective QR Codes]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/07/5-tips-for-highly-effective-qr-codes/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/07/5-tips-for-highly-effective-qr-codes</id>
  <published>2012-07-31T12:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2012-07-31T12:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seems like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QR_code&quot;&gt;QR codes&lt;/a&gt; are everywhere these days. Yes, literally everywhere, from restaurant tables to Train station to bananas. (Can you believe it? On Bananas!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/banana-qr-code-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Banana qr code small&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While their usage is not quite mainstream (yet), it is growing steadily and I expect the adoption to really take off when iOS joins the other popular mobile platforms (Android and to some Windows Phone) and supports QR Code natively.  There are helpful posts on  &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/29449/How-to-Create-a-QR-Code-in-4-Quick-Steps.aspx&quot;&gt;how to create your qrcode in 4 easy steps&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/30678/9-Unique-Ways-to-Generate-Leads-With-QR-Codes.aspx&quot;&gt;how they can be used to generate leads&lt;/a&gt; . In this post, I&amp;#39;ll give you some power-user tips to generate Robust QR Codes and increase your chances of conversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways a QR Code is like someone casually browsing your website. They start out as a casual onlooker of QR Code and ends up as a lead. If you think of it as a funnel (Like all marketers, I love funnels), here are five tips to make each step of the funnel effective :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.** Make your QR code attractive**: Yes, you read that right. You can make QR Codes attractive. For example, you can customize it with your logo, use the same colors as your brand or identity so that it attracts attention. A word of caution though, especially when you are trying fancy things like putting your logo on the QRCode). Anytime you manually do anything with the QRCode, make sure you test it thoroughly, ensure that it can be scanned and ensure that you haven&amp;#39;t accidentally corrupted the code itself). Sticking your logo at the center of the code, with a white border (like in the example below, should usually be good). Here are a couple of examples of customized QRCodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;]&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/qrcode.short_.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qrcode short&quot;&gt; Customized QR Code[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;]&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/qrcode.high_.gray-with-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qrcode high gray with logo&quot;&gt; QR Code Customized with Logo[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make your QR Code easy to scan&lt;/strong&gt;: Use a URL shortener so that you are encoding lesser information, and consider picking level H (for high level of error correction). A higher level of error correction increases the likelihood that your code will be scanned, even when it is exposed to adverse conditions (like bad weather, or the code is in a banana). Here is an example showing a QRCode with a long URL: http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/30678/9-Unique-Ways-to-Generate-Leads-With-QR-Codes.aspx and the same code but now representing a shortened URL: http://hub.am/NKxvQr Any guesses on which will be picked up faster by the phone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;]&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/qrcode.long_.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qrcode long url&quot;&gt; QR Code with regular, un-shortened URL[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;]&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/qrcode.short_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qrcode short url&quot;&gt; QR Code with shortened URL has bigger &amp;quot;handles&amp;quot;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Make sure your QR Code takes to a mobile optimized page&lt;/strong&gt;: All your efforts in making your QRCode attractive will be of no use, if your leads land on a page that is not optimized for mobile. You should also consider content that is mobile friendly (such as a video)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Think beyond URLs&lt;/strong&gt; : Think beyond URLs, make it contextual and make it relevant. For example, A QR code in a business card should be that of a VCF file. Remember that QR Codes are not restricted to just URLs. You can have QR codes for a lot of different categories including YouTube Videos, Google Maps Location, Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, FourSquare, Telephone Number, SMS Message, Email Address, Email Message, Contact Details (VCARD), Event (VCALENDAR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Try, Measure, Fix, Repeat:&lt;/strong&gt; QR Codes are a great way to bridge the gap between online and offline marketing. Use utm_campaign codes using a tracking URL builder when encoding your URLs (which gives you one more reason to use a URL shortener). If you use these codes, you can exactly tell how many visits you are getting from the QR Code and how many of those are converting to leads&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you used QR Codes successfully in your marketing campaigns? How did you make the most out of it?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/07/5-tips-for-highly-effective-qr-codes/&quot;&gt;5 Tips for Highly Effective QR Codes&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on July 31, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Focus on Intent, not Implementation]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/04/focus-on-intent-not-implementation/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/04/focus-on-intent-not-implementation</id>
  <published>2012-04-24T15:28:24Z</published>
  <updated>2012-04-24T15:28:24Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When talking to your customers and users, it is important to synthesize the information to make sure you are not just &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/show/15297&quot;&gt;delivering faster horses&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; (and apparently, there is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2011/08/henry_ford_never_said_the_fast.html&quot;&gt;no evidence that Henry Ford actually said it,&lt;/a&gt; but I&lt;img src=&quot;http://29.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l4srykesbA1qz6pqio1_500.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt; digress). When you are working onbrand new features, you likely are talking to a lot of power users and early adopters. Given how well they know about your current product, it is quite likely that they will tell you not only the &amp;quot;what&amp;quot; of the feature but also give you insights on the &amp;quot;how&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So It becomes important to distinguish between what the user says by way of implementation and what the user&amp;#39;s real intent is. There are a couple of cues that can alert you to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is the user focusing on the feature or are they talking about the benefit they&amp;#39;d derive from the feature? (To continue the faster horse analogy above, are they asking for shinier new wheels with additional spare wheels (which are features), or are they wishing that they get to a place faster (which is a benefit)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://scotchandcode.com/2011/11/23/356/&quot;&gt;Scotch and Code&lt;/a&gt;, I found another useful way. When the user is talking about the feature/app, are they saying &amp;quot;IT can do this&amp;quot; or are they saying &amp;quot;I can do this&amp;quot;. This subtle shift in perspective is a cue on whether the user is focusing and more importantly give a sense for whether the user thinks of your app as a tool that empowers them to do what they want to accomplish. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, here is a good example of how the focus is on the user&amp;#39;s intent. The Spilt keyboard in the iPad, accounts for the fact that people are going to tap on the empty spaces near the keys along the edge AND it guesses the user&amp;#39;s intent and magically makes those taps in empty spaces to the adjoining letter. Here is an illustration of this nifty trick: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/ios-split-keyboard-hidden-keys.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ios split keyboard hidden keys&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Image via &lt;a href=&quot;http://ios.finerthingsin.com/post/16982049392/ipad-keyboard-phantom-buttons&quot;&gt;http://ios.finerthingsin.com/post/16982049392/ipad-keyboard-phantom-buttons&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go ahead, try it out in your iPad. This is a classic example of focusing on the user&amp;#39;s intent, and not on the specifics of a given implementation. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/04/focus-on-intent-not-implementation/&quot;&gt;Focus on Intent, not Implementation&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on April 24, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whats on the Boston Mobile Community's Mind]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/02/whats-on-the-boston-mobile-communitys-mind/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/02/whats-on-the-boston-mobile-communitys-mind</id>
  <published>2012-02-28T21:00:15Z</published>
  <updated>2012-02-28T21:00:15Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went to the MassMobile - Mobile Developers Meetup, organized by Localytics, yesterday. There was a very lively discussion, with participants sharing stories of what worked, what didn&amp;#39;t, and what they are trying now.  Here are my key takeaways / quick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;summary of the meet up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/NewImage.png&quot; alt=&quot;NewImage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ice Cream Sandwich is not in anyone&amp;#39;s radar right now. Almost everyone is still thinking about 2.2 and 2.3. (Except maybe Google, which seems to be looking ahead. Looks Like&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/28/forget-about-android-4-0-google-exec-hints-android-5-0-will-launch-in-fall-of-2012/?grcc=33333Z98&quot;&gt; Android 5.0 aka jellybean is coming up soon&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were not a lot of real-life pain points around &lt;a href=&quot;http://anand.am/ApkpCk&quot;&gt;Fragmentation&lt;/a&gt; (yet?!). There wasn&amp;#39;t anyone that had to resort to &lt;a href=&quot;http://anand.am/wqu8wX&quot;&gt;device specific builds&lt;/a&gt; or anything funky like that. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone is still developing native apps over HTML5 sites. A couple of folks had gone down the path of HTML5 before deciding to go native largely due to poor user experience on HTML 5. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of interest on the so-called &amp;quot;Hybrid apps&amp;quot;. A few people had prototyped using frameworks such as jQuery Mobile, PhoneGap, but nothing in the market  yet. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were not a lot of folks developing for Multiple platforms (such as Android and iOS). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of discussion on how developing for Android would be different than developing for iOS. Three key themes emerged: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actual coding is roughly the same between the two platforms. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android has higher demands for testing, due to the varied types of devices and configuration. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android has slightly higher UX cost, given the different screen resolutions. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows 7 is still &amp;lt; 5% of the total market share. Apparently, the developer tools are great and development is really easy. Hopefully there will soon be people that actually use it, so we can build some apps for it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Raj and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.localytics.com/&quot;&gt;Localytics&lt;/a&gt; team for making it useful and informative.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/02/whats-on-the-boston-mobile-communitys-mind/&quot;&gt;Whats on the Boston Mobile Community's Mind&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on February 28, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Personas End to End]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/01/using-personas-end-to-end/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/01/using-personas-end-to-end</id>
  <published>2012-01-20T15:54:39Z</published>
  <updated>2012-01-20T15:54:39Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I guess this one should be filed under &amp;quot;Duh&amp;quot;. The use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Persona_(marketing&quot;&gt;personas&lt;/a&gt;) is pretty common while defining user interfaces and is a valuable tool in defining use cases, usage scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4093/4852756417_5171fc7b35.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Personas&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a very logical next step as you move from the what to build (through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startuplessonslearned.com/2008/11/what-is-customer-development.html&quot;&gt;Customer Development&lt;/a&gt;) to the actual building (Product Development). The &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kissmetrics.com&quot;&gt;KissMetrics blog&lt;/a&gt; has a an interesting post today on how you can use Personas to define your SEO Keywords. When figuring out which keywords to optimize for (and bid), it is especially important to speak the &amp;quot;user&amp;#39;s tongue&amp;quot;. Use of the right terminology is not only important within your product, but it is even more important to get it right, to make sure you get your positioning right. Personas help refine the SEO key terms and I think are also a great way to figure out which segment works well and which ones don&amp;#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have used some of the underlying techniques here, I have never actively thought of extending personas in the context of SEO. Overall, a great read. Check out the the entire blog post at the KissMetrics blog at &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/T8LtL&quot;&gt;How User Personas Can Improve Your SEO Strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2012/01/using-personas-end-to-end/&quot;&gt;Using Personas End to End&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on January 20, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android Fragmentation - Visualized]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/10/android-fragmentation-visualized/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/10/android-fragmentation-visualized</id>
  <published>2011-10-27T18:59:36Z</published>
  <updated>2011-10-27T18:59:36Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog post (and graphic) drives home the how manufacturers are not updating Android frequently (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/10things/10-things-i-hate-about-developing-for-android-and-some-workarounds-that-help/2650&quot;&gt;my Top 10 peeve with the platform&lt;/a&gt;). A few of the stats really jump out at me: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/android-frag.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/android-frag.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;10 of 18 were at least two major versions behind well within their two year contract period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;15 of 18 don’t run Gingerbread, which shipped in December 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://theunderstatement.com/post/11982112928/android-orphans-visualizing-a-sad-history-of-support&quot;&gt;Android Orphans&lt;/a&gt; blog post to get all the information.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/10/android-fragmentation-visualized/&quot;&gt;Android Fragmentation - Visualized&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on October 27, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thank you, Steve]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/10/thank-you-steve/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/10/thank-you-steve</id>
  <published>2011-10-06T11:40:53Z</published>
  <updated>2011-10-06T11:40:53Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Steve for inspiring me to create technology that &amp;quot;just works&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Steve for proving to me that technology doesn&amp;#39;t have to be clunky, messy and awkward&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Steve for helping me appreciate beautiful design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You sure put a ding in the universe. I promise to Stay Hungry and Stay Foolish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/t_hero.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rest In Peace.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/10/thank-you-steve/&quot;&gt;Thank you, Steve&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on October 06, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Know Thy Mobile User]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/know-thy-mobile-user/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/know-thy-mobile-user</id>
  <published>2011-08-20T14:17:34Z</published>
  <updated>2011-08-20T14:17:34Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Knowing your users and the context in which they are using your app is a key aspect of developing useful and user-engaged mobile apps. This is especially important in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://techrepublic.com/blog/10things/10-things-i-hate-about-developing-for-android-and-some-workarounds-that-help/2650&quot;&gt;fragmented market&lt;/a&gt; (and a recurring theme in the&lt;a href=&quot;http://techrepublic.com/blog/10things/10-things-i-hate-about-developing-for-android-and-some-workarounds-that-help/2650&quot;&gt; frustrations of developers&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hunch.com/?p=51781&quot;&gt;The Hunch Blog&lt;/a&gt; has some interesting stats on broad demographics and patterns of iOS and Android users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aka-img-2.h-img.com/media/img/blog/droid-vs-ios-inline.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/android-vs-ios.png&quot; alt=&quot;Android vs ios&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few that I found especially relevant to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stat:&lt;/strong&gt; iOS users also travel frequently. (They are 50% more likely to have visited more than five countries and 55% more likely to have used their frequent flyer miles). &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Takeaway&lt;/strong&gt;: Optimize your app for slower data connections and Be sure to test your app in &amp;quot;Airplane mode&amp;quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stat:&lt;/strong&gt; iOS users are 26% more likely to  prefer spending their money and Android users are 29% more likely to prefer saving their money .&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Takeaway&lt;/strong&gt;: Charge for your iOS apps :-) even if it is just 99 cents&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;Stat: *&lt;/em&gt;iOS Users are early adopters, 50% more likely to first use the Internet before &amp;#39;92 and 67% more likely to back up their computer constantly. &lt;br&gt;
*&lt;em&gt;Takeaway: *&lt;/em&gt;This is further confirmation that iCloud is going to have a lot of potential. You start with a user base that backs up constantly and then give them a very easy way for their data to be available everywhere. If you have iOS apps and weren&amp;#39;t already considering iCloud, you should. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Interesting stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Android users are 10% more likely to be men and iOS users are 10% more likely to be women.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;iOS users are 50% more likely to text while driving. (Seriously!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Android users are 50% more likely to use Yahoo! Mail. (Maybe this bodes well for &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/18/japan-to-get-android-based-yahoo-phone-next-month/&quot;&gt;Yahoo&amp;#39;s upcoming Android phone&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any other broad based demographics, analyze it in the context of your users and be sure not to confuse correlation with causation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/know-thy-mobile-user/&quot;&gt;Know Thy Mobile User&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on August 20, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Buys Motorola Mobility - This is good for users and product managers alike]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/google-buys-motorola-mobility-this-is-good-for-users-and-product-managers-alike/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/google-buys-motorola-mobility-this-is-good-for-users-and-product-managers-alike</id>
  <published>2011-08-15T12:33:42Z</published>
  <updated>2011-08-15T12:33:42Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2011/08/supercharging-android-google-to-acquire.html&quot;&gt;Google just announced&lt;/a&gt; that it is acquiring Motorola Mobility (&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/15/breaking-google-buys-motorola-for-12-5-billion/&quot;&gt;reportedly for $12.5 billion&lt;/a&gt;). This could be really good news for the end-to-end user experience in the Android platform. Google is also committing to keep the Android platform open. To quote the blog post :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This acquisition will not change our commitment to run Android as an open platform. Motorola will remain a licensee of Android and Android will remain open. We will run Motorola as a separate business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/android-motorola.png&quot; alt=&quot;Android motorola&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see this as Google taking a cautious step in the right direction in the whole debate on &amp;quot;Open&amp;quot; vs &amp;quot;Integrated&amp;quot;. It&amp;#39;d be great if Google can find the perfect balance, but if it can&amp;#39;t, I&amp;#39;d much rather it move towards Integrated rather than staying open.&lt;strong&gt;The mobile (and tablet) industry is converging on a single playbook for succeeding in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/8301-13860_3-20006526-56.html&quot;&gt;post-PC era&lt;/a&gt;. It involves hardware and software from the same vendor, providing a rich user experience&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the third of the marriages of hardware + software vendor, following RIM&amp;#39;s purchase of QNX, HP&amp;#39;s purchase of Palm for WebOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really good news for users and developers alike. The one recurring theme in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/10things/10-things-i-hate-about-developing-for-android-and-some-workarounds-that-help/2650&quot;&gt;Top 10 things that I hate about Android&lt;/a&gt; was fragmentation. Assuming that Google provides a strong baseline implementation, this will force other manufacturers to follow suit otherwise, over time, only Google&amp;#39;s phone will be selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could also mean that Xoom 2 (or 3),  might be a good viable alternative to iPad 2. Right now, it doesn&amp;#39;t even come close, but with a converged &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenextweb.com/google/2011/08/11/first-shots-of-android-ice-cream-sandwich-show-hot-new-look/&quot;&gt;OS for mobile and tablet (Ice-cream sandwich)&lt;/a&gt;, and hardware from the same vendor, and with Android&amp;#39;s reach, we might very well be looking at 2012 as the year of the iPad competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck Google!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/google-buys-motorola-mobility-this-is-good-for-users-and-product-managers-alike/&quot;&gt;Google Buys Motorola Mobility - This is good for users and product managers alike&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on August 15, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Product Manager's nightmares with the Android Platform]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/a-product-managers-nightmare-with-the-android/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/a-product-managers-nightmare-with-the-android</id>
  <published>2011-08-11T10:50:31Z</published>
  <updated>2011-08-11T10:50:31Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My observations on the pain points of developing for the Android platform, and suggested workarounds for those pain points are published today in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/10things/10-things-i-hate-about-developing-for-android-and-some-workarounds-that-help/2650&quot;&gt;TechRepublic&lt;/a&gt;. To summarize a few key points :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fragmentation is a nightmare and makes Android development a lot more complicated than it should be. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There should be broad based agreements on what manufacturers and carriers can and cannot do to the platform, and the ecosystem should work together to provide a good, solid baseline that all developers can take or granted. It is in the best interest of the platform&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google should act as a &amp;quot;good cop&amp;quot; in helping the platform as it matures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patent related issues (aka &amp;quot;The Pink Elephant in the room&amp;quot;) need to be addressed sooner than later. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read the entire blog post at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techrepublic.com/blog/10things/10-things-i-hate-about-developing-for-android-and-some-workarounds-that-help/2650&quot;&gt;TechRepublic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, I&amp;#39;d like to leave you with an image (From Engadget) that I think captures the gist of all things wrong about the platform. Think about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.blogcdn.com/www.engadget.com/media/2010/12/10x1207gj73s8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Android Fragmentations&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/a-product-managers-nightmare-with-the-android/&quot;&gt;A Product Manager's nightmares with the Android Platform&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on August 11, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marketing 101 : Positioning and Communicating Benefits]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/marketing-101-positioning-and-communicating-benefits/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/marketing-101-positioning-and-communicating-benefits</id>
  <published>2011-08-08T17:00:02Z</published>
  <updated>2011-08-08T17:00:02Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is fun to watch a real life case-study of sorts playing out in the battle of the tablets. There is the iPad 2, selling users on the experience, the emotional tug of Facetime, about how doctors and teachers and kids love the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there are the Android tablets selling specs, processors, gigahertz, dual-core, Adobe Flash and a good dose of WTF!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sethclifford.me/stream/2011/7/25/why-yes-that-is-a-galaxy-tab-101-in-my-pocket.html&quot;&gt;Seth Clifford&lt;/a&gt; (thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daringfireball.net&quot;&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt;) notes how a Staples manager says that a lot of people are returning Galaxy Tabs. To quote from the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Oh, ok, because we&amp;#39;re selling a lot of these things, and we get a LOT of them back. People buy them thinking they&amp;#39;re getting rid of a laptop, and they all come back returning them.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what happens when you sell on features and not on benefits. This is what happens if you muddy the positioning of your product. Looks like we are all going to have start thinking about 2012 as the year of the iPad competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/marketing-101-positioning-and-communicating-benefits/&quot;&gt;Marketing 101 : Positioning and Communicating Benefits&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on August 08, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back After a Break]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/back-after-a-break/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/back-after-a-break</id>
  <published>2011-08-08T04:18:52Z</published>
  <updated>2011-08-08T04:18:52Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been a hectic past few months. We launched our mobile apps for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.officedrop.com/iphone-pdf&quot;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.officedrop.com/android-paper-to-go&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, and also launched our partnership with Nuance Communications to launch &lt;a href=&quot;http://paperport.com&quot;&gt;PaperPort Anywhere&lt;/a&gt;, the cloud-powered version of PaperPort software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolling out the two mobile apps, a tablet app was exciting, to say the least. You can expect a lot more of my thoughts on those in the coming days (and fanboys always have an opinion, don&amp;#39;t they?!). Meanwhile, you are welcome to catch up on my guest blog posts :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kissmetrics.com/1-2-punch-for-increasing-conversion/&quot;&gt;KissMetrics blog&lt;/a&gt;, I write about how we increased conversion in OfficeDrop by listening to our customers, leads and effectively using those tools. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;My chat with Morgan Friberg of Atlassian about &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.atlassian.com/news/2011/04/case_study_issue_tracking_and_agile_development_at_officedro.html&quot;&gt;how we do Product Development at OfficeDrop&lt;/a&gt; and how Jira helps us develop markets that people love and use! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned, and happy to be writing again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/NewImage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Break Over.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/08/back-after-a-break/&quot;&gt;Back After a Break&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on August 08, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show some personality in your apps]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/05/show-some-personality-in-your-apps/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/05/show-some-personality-in-your-apps</id>
  <published>2011-05-09T12:30:08Z</published>
  <updated>2011-05-09T12:30:08Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A great way to be friendly to your customers is to project some personality in your apps (and hopefully it reflects your company&amp;#39;s true personality).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/logos/&quot;&gt;Google Doodles&lt;/a&gt; are pretty popular and it is a pretty good proof that you can show off stuff, even though there isn&amp;#39;t much in your &amp;quot;home page&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a couple of nice examples this week that I thought I would share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailchimp.com&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;. On May 4th, their login page had been updated to reflect &amp;quot;Star wars day&amp;quot;, aka, May the 4th be with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/force-1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/force-1-1024x648.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other example I found was for the release notes for the Yelp iPhone App (And yes, you can judge me by the fact that I read release notes of the apps I use)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/yelp-update.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/yelp-update.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both are nice examples that bring a smile to your customer&amp;#39;s face when they come across them. Well done. How do you make your apps have a personality?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/05/show-some-personality-in-your-apps/&quot;&gt;Show some personality in your apps&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on May 09, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delight your customers by paying attention to the little things]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/05/delight-your-customers-by-paying-attention-to-the-little-things/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/05/delight-your-customers-by-paying-attention-to-the-little-things</id>
  <published>2011-05-09T02:47:16Z</published>
  <updated>2011-05-09T02:47:16Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks back my trusted (rusted?) 3 year old MacBook pro wouldn&amp;#39;t boot. By the sounds of it, it was pretty obvious that it wasn&amp;#39;t something I could fix / hack, so I took it to the local Apple store. I had put on my &amp;quot;I am a Mac&amp;quot; T-shirt hoping to score some brownie points at the genius bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick diagnosis at the genius bar showed that the motherboard had likely conked. So it had to shipped to their depot to have it replaced. The extended apple care warranty had just expired, but the &amp;quot;genius&amp;quot; at the genius bar was gracious enough to &amp;quot;let it slide&amp;quot; and told me he would take care of it without charging anything. Wow!! That&amp;#39;s probably a good $300 worth of repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to have received my machine back in 5 to 7 business days, but lo and behold, I got a call in just 2 days saying my machine was ready. Woot. Awesome Apple. But wait, there is more. Not only was the logic board replaced, Apple had also replaced the optical drive and two fans, since they were not in &amp;quot;good condition&amp;quot;. What a nice gesture. But wait, there is even more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/20110508-104430.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/20110508-104430.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mahatma-Gandhi-customer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the rubber pads at the bottom of the MacBook had fallen off. I was curious what they had done about it and sure enough all four of them were replaced. I mean, who cares about the rubber pads at the bottom, except of course the user. You don&amp;#39;t even have to be a fanboy like me, to be impressed by such attention to detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was happy enough when Apple fixed my machine for free, even though it was out of warranty. But such attention to detail truly delights your customers. It demonstrates empathy, and it shows your customer that you care about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fixing something with a bunch of goodies makes your customers happy. Going above and beyond what is needed and paying attention to detail delights them enough to write a blog post about it and tell the story to everyone in their inner circle of friends and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you delighting your customers?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/05/delight-your-customers-by-paying-attention-to-the-little-things/&quot;&gt;Delight your customers by paying attention to the little things&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on May 09, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[ProductCamp Boston is on April 2, 2011]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/productcamp-boston-is-on-april-2-2011/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/productcamp-boston-is-on-april-2-2011</id>
  <published>2011-03-18T03:47:16Z</published>
  <updated>2011-03-18T03:47:16Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://productcampboston.org/&quot;&gt;ProductCamp Boston&lt;/a&gt;, the awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unconference&quot;&gt;unconference&lt;/a&gt; on Product Management, returns on Saturday, April 2, 2011 at the Microsoft New England Research and Development Center in Cambridge. I have been to prior year&amp;#39;s ProductCamps and they rock!  (I am pretty bummed that I can&amp;#39;t make it this year, because I will be out of the country at that time.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/ProductCampBoston.png&quot; alt=&quot;ProductCampBoston&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with UnConferences, you should definitely go to this one. There are no “attendees,” since everyone participates in some manner.  At ProductCamp, you’ll get to present, lead a roundtable discussion, share your experiences, and/or volunteer. Every single unconference that I have gone to (such as the MassTLC unconference, ProductCamp and BarCamp), has been memorable and insightful. They are a great way to meet fellow Product Managers and share ideas and exchange notes on common challenges, industry trends and network!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;#39;s theme is “Innovation” – and it’s all about product, process and personal innovation to help you and your company win. You get to propose topics, deliver talks, attend sessions all around that theme. So what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://productcampboston.org/register/&quot;&gt;Register Now&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://productcampboston.org/2011/03/17/how-to-propose-a-session-in-7-steps/&quot;&gt;Propose a Session&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, tell me all about it, since I cant be there. Oh! and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/pcampboston&quot;&gt;you should also follow ProductCamp on twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/productcamp-boston-is-on-april-2-2011/&quot;&gt;ProductCamp Boston is on April 2, 2011&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on March 18, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nope, I am not sick of SXSW. I am excited to go there.. ]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/nope-i-am-not-sick-of-sxsw-i-am-excited-to-go-there/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/nope-i-am-not-sick-of-sxsw-i-am-excited-to-go-there</id>
  <published>2011-03-10T04:27:44Z</published>
  <updated>2011-03-10T04:27:44Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first &lt;a href=&quot;http://sxsw.com&quot;&gt;SXSW&lt;/a&gt; and I am excited. I dont care &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2011/03/07/sxsgah/&quot;&gt;what the naysayers say&lt;/a&gt;, I am determined to have a fun time, especially while meeting our customers as part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesmallbusinessweb.com&quot;&gt;the Small business web&lt;/a&gt; Party! (and &lt;a href=&quot;http://startable.com&quot;&gt;Healy Jones&lt;/a&gt; will be joining me too!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/sxsw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Sxsw&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Lean Startup tracks, I am also looking forward to the tracks on User Interface Design (iPad Design, Metrics Driven Design to name a few). It should be fun to bump into some familiar &lt;a href=&quot;http://bostinnovation.com/2011/03/07/boston-all-up-in-sxswi-preview-sxswbos/?ref=act&amp;amp;buid=0&quot;&gt;Boston area peeps&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bostoninaustinsxsw.eventbrite.com/#m_1_200&quot;&gt;Boston In Austin happy hour&lt;/a&gt;. I booked an apartment through &lt;a href=&quot;http://airbnb.com&quot;&gt;AirBnB&lt;/a&gt; (my first time, so lets hope this works out!) and I have also armed myself with the latest versions of Foursquare, Groupme, Beluga and Plancast. Austin, here I come!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you going to South-by? Here is a quick embed from my Plancast feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, here are some tips on how to be South by South Best! &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/nope-i-am-not-sick-of-sxsw-i-am-excited-to-go-there/&quot;&gt;Nope, I am not sick of SXSW. I am excited to go there.. &lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on March 10, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to tell your customers that you screwed up?]]></title>
  <link>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/how-to-tell-your-customers-that-you-screwed-up/</link>
  <id>http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/how-to-tell-your-customers-that-you-screwed-up</id>
  <published>2011-03-01T18:42:49Z</published>
  <updated>2011-03-01T18:42:49Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anand Rajaram</name>
    <uri>http://anandrajaram.github.io</uri>
    <email>anandrajaram@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By now, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#search?q=gmail&quot;&gt;Everything that needs to be said &lt;/a&gt;about the Gmail outage has been said. Maybe not, until I have added my 2 cents. Haha.  I was curious &lt;a href=&quot;http://gmailblog.blogspot.com/2011/02/gmail-back-soon-for-everyone.html&quot;&gt;what Google would say in this matter&lt;/a&gt; and how they would react. Similar to my earlier post on the&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/2011/01/anatomy-of-an-apple-email/&quot;&gt; Anatomy of a customer service email&lt;/a&gt;, here are my thoughts on Google&amp;#39;s well written blog post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_223&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;622&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Gmail Outage Blog Post Analysis&amp;quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Official-Gmail-Blog.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.startupproductmanager.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Official-Gmail-Blog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gmail Outage Blog Post&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say, sorry, straight up. Not wishy washy, not the &amp;quot;We apologize for any inconvenienced this may have sort of caused&amp;quot; kind, but a straight up one human to another kind. Sorry!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now give them the good news on how you have rectified the issue. Provide details on how many were impacted, what the impact was and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, provide an explanation. Many people may just care about the first two items (the fact that they are apologizing and why it is ok now). If you do need an explanation, provide a meaningful one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Provide a concrete timeline on when the issue will be resolved. This is one missing component from this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk about why this won&amp;#39;t happen again. The post only alludes to it, it could have done a better job on this front.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apologize again and end on an empathetic / positive forward looking comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How have you communicated bad news to your customers? Do you think Google&amp;#39;s response is adequate? Does it convince you?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io/2011/03/how-to-tell-your-customers-that-you-screwed-up/&quot;&gt;How to tell your customers that you screwed up?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Anand Rajaram at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anandrajaram.github.io&quot;&gt;Startup Product Manager&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
